<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blair Rorani</title>
    <description>I&#39;m design tools that help people and organisations create change.</description>
    <link>http://blair.rorani.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blair.rorani.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Engagement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/engagement.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement is a super important business word and at the same time it can be a pretty fluffy term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What business people call engagement can be thought of as a combination of &lt;strong&gt;alignment&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;action&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone involved in creating change (deciders and doers) needs a shared view of the current world and how the future will be different and better. Priorities, goals, rewards, resources etc. all need to be aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees and/or customers need to know what problem is being solved, what the proposed solution is and how it will make it easier to achieve a particular thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately most businesses communication defaults to an email or maybe a town hall. Emails can have lots of important, accurate information in them. But there is just so much email. Open your work email inbox now and see for your self. How much impact will another email have? Emails clog your short terms memory and create stress with all the additional tasks they create for you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email is also not a highly visual medium. File size and the design tools and skills available make creating effective visual emails pretty difficult. So you&amp;#39;re stuck with lots of important, accurate words that most people will have to ignore along with lots of other emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change designers know that people learn and recall information much better when it is &lt;a href=&quot;/getting-clarity-story-design/&quot;&gt;presented as a story&lt;/a&gt;. Can you remember any books you read or were read to you as a child? Now you don&amp;#39;t remember the exact words, but you can probably retell the story. What about a movie you saw years ago? Brilliant. What if all business communication was just as effective. Stories can involve emotion. When we feel something we are more likely to do something (feeling angry = shouting, feeling hungry = eating, you get the idea).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with stories change designers use &lt;a href=&quot;/visual-literacy-for-project-teams&quot;&gt;visuals&lt;/a&gt;. Visuals clarify what communicators mean when they are using words alone. They can also be memorable (if they are relevant vs. decorative e.g. most stock photos of hand shakes). A visual story is a powerful communication tool, far more powerful than email can ever be. Plus visual content is shared far more across today&amp;#39;s digital networks. In fact, a picture of words in a book is often more popular than the same text copied and posted into a social network post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re in the learning and development or training industry you&amp;#39;ll often be asked to design training. Training (think elearning, slides, user guides) are basically tools for providing information (probably with a quiz at the end). These tools typically aren&amp;#39;t about producing action. They are focussed on compliance and telling people information before they actually need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools that enable action are used by people practising a skill in a real or simulated situation. Yes you might need to provide information to people while they are practising. The difference between traditional training and enabling action is that people are putting that info to use and referring to it where and when they need it, not just so they can click through another elearning course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change designers use stories, visual communication, games, digital technology and design thinking to create alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick example that most people can relate to is a healthy diet. Yes you can read a book about healthy diets and recipes. The problem is that this is a tool for information delivery. What are you going to do next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open your smart phone&amp;#39;s app store and search for recipe or healthy eating apps, you not only get the recipes but often you can create a shopping list based on the ingredients you are missing from your kitchen. Then you can take you phone to the shop and tick off the missing ingredients as you buy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when you get home you can fire up your app and most likely watch a video of how to prepare the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus if recording exercise, weighing or measuring is part of what you&amp;#39;re trying to achieve with your health, the healthy eating or another app can remind you to exercise and measure and even help you record you results so you can see you progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while most businesses are in the mode of training (information delivery), tools that enable action will always be more effective at creating change because they are available in context (where and when you need them) and they provide practical information and even progress tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What tools do you use to create engagement at your company?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/creating-engagement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/creating-engagement/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why visual meetings?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke at the LearnX event in Sydney about the value of visual meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my slides from the event (presenter not included so you&amp;#39;ll lose some context but at least you can look at the pictures).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&quot;speakerdeck-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;06d1848872a1479cb4e957d87bc3c37c&quot; data-ratio=&quot;1.33333333333333&quot; src=&quot;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to learn how you can use the power of visuals to get greater clarity at the start of your next project? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:blair@rorani.com&quot;&gt;Send me a quick email&lt;/a&gt; and let me know you saw me at LearnX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/learnx/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/learnx/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apps as coaches</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/friendly-apps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apps&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messaging apps are becoming a big deal. I personally use &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; all the time, as does my family. The point is, messaging apps are becoming the main communication tools for many people. Here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/messaging-apps-just-getting-started/&quot;&gt;some brilliant insights into the possible future of messaging apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aspect of this article I found interesting was the idea of suggested responses. The examples in the article relate to booking a lift with Uber or buying movie tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Just as keyboard features like QuickType on iOS suggest words you might like to make, the messaging app could suggest entire messages:&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that if an app becomes aware that you want to accomplish something it presents some options for you to choose. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I need a lift home&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I need a lift to work&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a huge fan of &lt;em&gt;apps as coaches&lt;/em&gt;. For this to work well an app needs access to some data about you and your context in order to make suggestions that will assist instead of annoy. Apps as coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now think about how training traditionally works. What if instead of taking a present-and-memorise approach, you used an app that could both push and pull information to you in context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if I&amp;#39;m at the airport my banking app on my phone knows to offer me info about banking when overseas. How does it do this? It simply knows my location (the airport) and it sends me a notification that I can take action on or dismiss. The notification is relevant and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine bringing that same functionality into a training situation. If I&amp;#39;m near a certain piece of equipment my device can push a notification that asks me if I want to get some tips on using the equipment safely and correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of if an app has access to my calendar and it knows I&amp;#39;m going into a sales call the app can offer me sales tips or offer to show me some CRM info on the person I&amp;#39;m meeting with or link me to their social network profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app does this by offering me suggested commands I can give it. For example: &amp;quot;I want some sales tips&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I want to see Dave&amp;#39;s purchase history&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I can google sales tips or look up Dave&amp;#39;s CRM data myself. But this is just one example of how apps can have a conversation with us and take away the need to remember so many things. They can bring possible actions to our attention we may be blind to because of repetition or familiarity. They can help to add an element of automation and reduce cognitive load. Apps as coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you already use an app that works something like this? How could you make use of an app as a coach?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/apps-as-coaches/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/apps-as-coaches/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Clarity with Story Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/change-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;clarity, alignment and action&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about the work that you do it will almost always involve some sort of change. A change in business results, in customer sign ups, in sales, productivity, in technology or organisation structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change cannot happen effectively unless you have all of the following factors taken care of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting clarity about a problem and possible solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aligning stakeholders (employees and/or customers) so they have a shared view of the problem and solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enabling action by those stakeholders (on-boarding, training, support, for new products or business processes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change design is about using design to maximise each of these factors (maximum clarity, maximum alignment and maximum action).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design isn&amp;#39;t only used to make things look nice. Nice logos, nice fonts, nice colours are all fine but that&amp;#39;s not really the type of design that you can use to create change. Design isn&amp;#39;t just how you make something look, design is a powerful tool for solving problems and communicate with clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five types of design that can be applied to any project so you can maximise clarity, alignment and action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;story design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visual design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;game design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;digital design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s take a look at story design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Story design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories add context to information. This means that they make it meaningful and memorable. To create change you need to take information about your stakeholders and be able to tell the story of what they are trying to accomplish, what pains they currently experience and what gains they can create. This increases empathy which is a key to designing some thing people actually want and need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If stakeholders&amp;#39; pains and gains are addressed by a solution then you need to be able to tell the story of how the future could be in terms of a new product, a new use of technology, a new way of working, etc. You can then test the viability, desirability and feasibility of a solution with stakeholders without having to build something. You can simply tell them a story featuring them, their problem and one possible solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an example of a special type of story you can design to get clarity when you&amp;#39;re trying to create change. It&amp;#39;s called a problem-solution story. (It&amp;#39;s one of the three types of stories we can use in business.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Reginald&amp;#39;s computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A problem-solution story contrasts the problems with doing things the current way and the benefits of doing them a new way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/broken-computer.png&quot; alt=&quot;broken computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Reginald is a professor here at the Brookings Institute. Late one night he was busy entering all the results of his students final exams into the computer in his classroom. Unfortunately, the computer crashed and Reginald lost all his work. This made Reginald’s boss and his students very upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Reginald and his fellow professors need more reliable computer systems for working with important data like exam results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/new-computer.png&quot; alt=&quot;new computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Bookings Institute has decided to upgrade all it’s computers so they are faster and almost never crash. The Institute is also using cloud technology to store their data. This means when Reginald enters exam results they are always saved automatically. No more lost data. Best of all, Reginald can access his files in the cloud from his home computer or his mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if Reginald needs to work a bit later than usual, he can do so from the comfort of his home office. Plus get lots of work done on the train ride home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the elements of this problem-solution story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reginald (a person who your audience can relate to and probably wants to accomplish the same thing they do)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reginald’s computer crashing (big problem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reginald’s boss and students getting upset (results of problem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster, crash-resistant computers (proposed solution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-save and working remotely and on the train (benefits of changing things)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/getting-clarity-story-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/getting-clarity-story-design/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Analog vs. Digital Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i2.wp.com/boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Screen-Shot-2015-06-16-at-11.50.32-AM.png?resize=600%2C332&quot; alt=&quot;Apps&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two interesting posts about the value of writing / drawing by hand using analog tools instead of defaulting to digital all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.austinkleon.com/post/110647355141&quot;&gt;Clive Thompson, “The Pencil and the Keyboard: How The Way You Write Changes the Way You Think”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2015/06/16/super-mario-maker-design.html&quot;&gt;Nintendo used to design Super Mario levels on graph paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of the smart phone where digital notebooks are everywhere, this can seem counter intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I often use a hybrid approach when creating stuff - I draw by hand (analog) on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/blairrorani/visual-note-taking/&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; (digital). This year in particular I&amp;#39;ve started to keep several paper notebooks, each for a different purpose. Drawing and writing by hand and colouring them with crayons is definitely enjoyable. As Clive points out, there are benefits to using digital or analog depending on the context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change design is firstly about getting clarity. Project teams can get clarity by using design thinking, which is collaborative but also very hands on (whiteboards, drawing, sticky notes, etc). Often in a meeting we&amp;#39;ll have Excel or Word or MS Project open and we&amp;#39;re typing notes into our phone and doing a whole lot of digital stuff. Not only is this thinking often kept to ourselves (only we see it) but it&amp;#39;s also the wrong tool set for big picture, brainstormy, problem solving. Analog tools are more effective for these ideation and design contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you use analog tools or do you default to digital (aka your laptop)? How have you used analog design methods to get clarity in meetings?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/analog-vs-digital-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/analog-vs-digital-design/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why you need a shared language</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple-triangle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apple and a triangle&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to solving business problems it is usually quite an unstructured, messy process. One of the main reasons is that we don&amp;#39;t have a shared language to use when discussing the change we want to see in a business. This makes it difficult, if not impossible, to get clarity on what we need to change and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have seen the &lt;a href=&quot;http://img.pandawhale.com/159329-Software-Engineering-Tree-Swin-iqRE.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tree swing diagram&lt;/a&gt; depicting what often happens to most change projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve tried to come up with an explanation of what role a shared language can play in helping business teams get clarity when they are trying to create change. Let&amp;#39;s look at Chefs as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chefs use a shared language when they solve food problems. For example, when they&amp;#39;re designing a menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In western culture, a menu usually has three areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entrées&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deserts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using design we can visualise these areas as a canvas that chefs could use to design a menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blank-canvas.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blank canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chefs probably follow a process to make sure the menu they design will work. They start with the entrées, then mains, then deserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/process.png&quot; alt=&quot;process&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within each area of our menu canvas there are probably some guidelines or rules for what should go in that area, what options they should consider and what makes a good dish. For example, roast pork probably goes in the &lt;em&gt;mains&lt;/em&gt; area and an entrée should be a small dish and could be finger food, a soup or a salad (I&amp;#39;m not an actual chef so apologies to all the chefs who are screwing up their eyebrows while reading this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rules.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rules&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu in it&amp;#39;s current form can then be tested with customers to see if it&amp;#39;s creating value for them. If not, it&amp;#39;s easy to use the shared language of menu design to make improvements over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;#39;ve got two elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A [design] canvas (or a visual, tactile tool)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A process to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together these elements give chefs a shared language they can use to get clarity about their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple-to-apple.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apple and apple&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like chefs we too can use design canvases to solve problems and create change in our businesses. They give us a visual framework within which to brainstorm and make decisions. Most importantly they can help us get clarity, sooner, and give us something tangible to test with stakeholders, learn from and improve on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: If you&amp;#39;ve got a design canvas you like please tweet or email me a link with a quick blurb about how you&amp;#39;ve used it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/why-you-need-a-shared-languge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/why-you-need-a-shared-languge/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design for change</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/design-for-change.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;design for change&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business teams who want to create change can get value from to using visual, story, game and digital design and design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m creating visual, tactile tools and a process to make that easy. The outcome will be a shared vocabulary and frameworks for understanding and applying &lt;strong&gt;change design&lt;/strong&gt; to business challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These could be a new vision or strategy, a technology or process change, a change in the minds of an audience, in the purchasing decisions of a customer or the skill level of employees or partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achieving any business goal requires change. Change design can help you get clarity on the desired outcome, achieve alignment with stakeholders and enable action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/design-for-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/design-for-change/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is engagement?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/creating-engagement&quot;&gt;Read the updated version of this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/engagement.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;engagement&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement is a super important business word and at the same time it can be a pretty fluffy term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What businesses normally call engagement is usually a combination of alignment and action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People need to agree on a shared view of the world and how the future will be different and better. Priorities, goals, rewards, resources etc all need to be aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change designers use stories, visual communication and design thinking to create alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shared world view about a particular thing is great but if it never leaves everyone&amp;#39;s heads and hearts nothing changes. People need to ability to act on what they now think and feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change designers use practical, visual, game-like tools to make taking action (practising and doing) easy and make progress visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you define and create engagement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/what-is-engagement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/what-is-engagement/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m creating something new</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog-images/change-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;change design&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m creating something new. I&amp;#39;m doing it in public so I can get reactions, feedback and co-design it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to draw my ideas and progress in a notebook with a pen sporadically coloured in with crayons. So expect lots of photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to design a product that teaches the tools and process of what I call &lt;strong&gt;change design&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What exactly is change design? Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d love to get you feedback, talk more or answer question about this. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/blairrorani&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:blair@rorani.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/im-creating-something-new/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/im-creating-something-new/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When information goes to jail</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/go-to-jail.png&quot; alt=&quot;Go to jail&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you play the board game Monopoly few things can bum you out more than landing on &amp;quot;Go to Jail&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;s not a nice place. You&amp;#39;re basically trapped there, unable to interact with the other players until they land on the jail space to visit you. While you&amp;#39;re in jail they&amp;#39;re busy buying all the good properties and preparing to punish you with houses and hotels when you get out. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the real world jail is a place we put people to segregate them from everyone else and limit our interaction with them. This is usually because there is something very negative about these people&amp;#39;s behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically jail = bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we know we live in the information age. This is an age where the creation and sharing of information is happening at a phenomenal rate. What can&amp;#39;t you find out simply by talking to your watch? Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the abundance of information in existence, I&amp;#39;ve observed that almost everything that learning and development professionals produce is effectively telling this information to &amp;quot;Go to jail&amp;quot;. Here&amp;#39;s how this works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Talk to an expert.
Step 2: Simplify and chunk what they know.
Step 3: Hopefully design some visuals.
Step 4: Put this accurate, simplified, visual information into an elearning module, workshop slides, a facilitator&amp;#39;s guide or an intranet site.
Step 5: The information is now trapped, unable to interact with people who need it unless they visit the module, workshop or intranet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop quiz: Is information easy to find on your intranet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We send information to jail when we present it in a &lt;em&gt;training&lt;/em&gt; context instead of in a &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; or using context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Perhaps it&amp;#39;s because teacher&amp;#39;s always had a book of answers or memorised answers when we were at school. Then along came the  CD-ROM and all of a sudden we could put the book of answers into a multimedia presentation on a disc and distribute the disc. The internet allowed us to distribute the same multimedia presentations to more people with greater ease. We decided that we should track who had accessed these presentations (now called online courses) and so we put the into database called an LMS. Of course we still need workshops too so we often put the info from the course into PowerPoint instead and read it out to people then we quiz them on what we just read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this is inherently evil. Until you need to access some of the information sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the scenarios listed above are training contexts. We leave the real world of our job,  fly to head office, stay over night and attend a two-day seminar. Attending seminars isn&amp;#39;t part of our job nor does the seminar necessarily include practising your job in a meaningful way. Again, it&amp;#39;s a training context. Or we click through an elearning course that is basically the same thing as the seminar only shorter and with drag and drop interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually need to use the information we are presented in a training context (well some of it) in a doing context i.e. when doing our jobs. So how do we get it? The instructions I need are on screen 18 of the elearning course or were explained after lunch on day two of the workshop and the trainer wrote some notes on a flip chart to summarise. How can I get that information from the training context into a doing context? For the most part it&amp;#39;s trapped. Or it&amp;#39;s on the intranet which, let&amp;#39;s face it, is basically the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how accurate or interesting or well presented or interactive the information was, we simply sent it to jail. It&amp;#39;s isolated from the real world. Timely access to information when
and where we need it (in context) is critical to success and survival
in today&amp;#39;s fast-paced world. It is often easy to access information that isn&amp;#39;t required to do our jobs from a computer or device with an internet connection. For example, the result of a big sports event or news about a celebrity. You can find a video about anything on YouTube . Although we don&amp;#39;t necessarily need this information we can access it when and where we want it (in context).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for me the question is: How can we make access to information in a doing context at work just as easy as it is at home? Or in other words: Let&amp;#39;s find new models for the work L and D produce and set
all that information free!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://blair.rorani.com/when-information-goes-to-jail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blair.rorani.com/when-information-goes-to-jail/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>